Wan-Cyuan (Chris) Fan

Personal website: https://sites.google.com/view/wancyuanfan

☑ christine5200312@gmail.com ☑ wancyuan@ntu.edu.tw

Introduction

Currently, I'm a research assistant at National Taiwan University (NTU) in Vision and Learning Lab advised by Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang. My research interests span the fields of Deep Learning (DL) and Computer Vision (CV), particularly multi-modal learning, text-to-image synthesis, x-to-video generation, and text-guided image manipulation.

Education

Sep 2020 – Jan 2022

M.Sc. Communication Engineering at National Taiwan University in Vision and Learning Lab advised by Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang GPA: 4.11 / 4.3

Sep 2015 - June 2020

■ **B.Sc. Electrical Engineering** at National Taiwan University GPA: 3.98 / 4.3

Work Experience

Sep. 2022 – Present

- Research Assistant in Vision and Learning Lab (VLL) at NTU advised by Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang
 - Build a text guided image manipulation network under weakly supervised setting
 - Learning scene layout generation with spatial and conceptual diversity

Mar. 2022 - Sep. 2022

- **Research Intern** in Azure Computer Vision Research at Microsoft
 - Working with Yen-Chun Chen, DongDong Chen, Yu Cheng, and Lu Yuan
 - Exploring a multi-scale diffusion and denoising strategies of the diffusion model for conditional complex scene image generation

July 2019 – Aug. 2020

- Student Research Intern in Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica, Taiwan, advised by Prof. Tyng-Luh Liu
 - Design models for the long-tailed object detection and instance segmentation tasks
 - Explore the adaptive batch-wise regularization for image classification under long-tailed and fine-grained distribution

July 2017 - Jan. 2018

- **Student Intern** in Digital Learning Center, National Taiwan University
 - Problem-solving using design thinking and activity planning

Research Publications

Pre-prints

- 1. **Wan-Cyuan Fan**, Yen-Chun Chen, Dong Dong Chen, Yu Cheng, Lu Yuan, Yu-Chiang Frank Wang. "Frido: Feature Pyramid Diffusion for Complex Scene Image Synthesis." In submission, 2022.
- 2. **Wan-Cyuan Fan**, Cheng-Fu Yang, Chiao-An Yang, Yu-Chiang Frank Wang. "Target-free Text-guided Image Manipulation." In submission, 2022.

- 3. **Wan-Cyuan Fan**, Cheng-Yao Hong, Yen-Chi Hsu, Tyng-Luh Liu. "IOU-Aware Multi-Expert Cascade Network via Dynamic Ensemble for Long-tailed Object Detection." In submission, 2022.
- 4. Yen-Chi Hsu, Cheng-Yao Hong, **Wan-Cyuan Fan**, Ming-Sui Lee, Davi Geiger, Tyng-Luh Liu. "ACE: Adaptive Confusion Energy for Natural World Data Distribution." In submission (journal), 2022.
- 5. **Wan-Cyuan Fan**. "Auto-drawer: Generating and Modifying Images Continually by Visual-Relational Knowledge Graph." Arxiv pre-print, 2019.

Conference Proceedings

- 1. Cheng-Fu Yang, Yao-Hung Hubert Tsai, **Wan-Cyuan Fan**, Yu-Chiang Frank Wang, Louis-Philippe Morency, Ruslan Salakhutdinov. "Paraphrasing Is All You Need for Novel Object Captioning." In Proceedings of the Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022.
- 2. Chiao-An Yang, Cheng-Yo Tan, **Wan-Cyuan Fan**, Cheng-Fu Yang, Meng-Lin Wu, Yu-Chiang Frank Wang. "Scene Graph Expansion for Semantics-Guided Image Outpainting." In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022.
- 3. Chih-Chun Yang, **Wan-Cyuan Fan**, Cheng-Fu Yang, Yu-Chiang Frank Wang. "Cross-Modal Mutual Learning for Audio-Visual Speech Recognition and Manipulation." In Proceedings of Thirty-Sixth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022.
- 4. Cheng-Fu Yang*, **Wan-Cyuan Fan***, Fu-En Yang, Yu-Chiang Frank Wang. "LayoutTransformer: Scene Layout Generation With Conceptual and Spatial Diversity." In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021.
- 5. **Wan-Cyuan Fan**, Cheng-Yao Hong, Yen-Chi Hsu, Tynh-Luh Liu. "Multi-expert heads of Long-tailed Instance Segmentation." Tech. Report of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (ECCV) workshop, 2020.

Miscellaneous Experience

Awards and Achievements

- Honorable Master Thesis Award, The Chinese Image Processing and Pattern Recognition Society, Taiwan.
- Master Student Research Scholarship, Novatek Foundation, Taiwan.
- **Top 10 Winner** (World Ranking 7), Large Vocabulary Instance Segmentation Challenge, ECCV workshop.
- **Third prize**, the Contest of Innovation and Entrepreneurship of Biotechnology of Ministry of Education, Taiwan.
- First prize, the Final Competition of the Clinical Application of Medical Electronic Device Course, National Taiwan University.
- First prize, the Final Competition of the Clinical Observation and Need Investigation Course, National Taiwan University.

Position of Responsibility

- **Vice leader of Public Relations Department** in the Aboriginal Service Club at National Taiwan University.
 - Manage the Public Relations Department and host the training courses and 2 days camp for almost 80 members.

Miscellaneous Experience (continued)

Professional Activity

2021-2022

Conference Reviewer or Program Commitee.

Thirty-Sixth Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022
Thirty-Seventh AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022
IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) (2020, 2021)
IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) (2021)
Thirty-Sixth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021

■ Teaching Assistant of the Course for the graduate students.

Deep Learning for Computer Vision, National Taiwan University (NTU), 2020 Deep Learning for Computer Vision, National Taiwan University (NTU), 2021